https://www.shopkit.com/privacy-policy/

Privacy Policy
Shopkit Group Ltd
We care about you and know that you care how information about you is used and shared and we appreciate your trust in us to do that carefully and sensibly. This notice describes the privacy policy of Shopkit Group Ltd. By visiting Shopkit Group Ltd, you are accepting and consenting to the practices described in this Privacy Notice.
We are committed to putting the consumer first and being transparent on how we collect, use and protect your personal information. The data controller is Shopkit Group Limited (referred to in this policy as “we”, “us” or “our”).
Our Privacy Policy is comprehensively explained here, but in a nutshell, we want you to be confident that the personal information you give us is safe and secure with us, and understand how we use it only for our core business purposes of marketing, selling and shipping our quality products and to offer you a better and more personalised experience on our main Website and on our Online Shop, and that we will never lease, distribute or sell your personal information to third parties.
Any personal information provided to or to be gathered by Shopkit Group Ltd is controlled by the Data Controller at:
Shopkit Group Ltd
Unit 3
Swanstons Road
Great Yarmouth
Norfolk NR30 3NQ
T: +44 (0)1923 818282
F: +44 (0)1493 330520
E: sales@shopkit.com
What Personal Information Do We Collect?
The information we collect from customers helps us personalise and continually improve your viewing and shopping experience on our main Website and our Online Shop. We use the information to handle orders, deliver products and services, process payments, communicate with you about orders, products, services and promotional offers, update our records and generally maintain your accounts with us. Here are the types of information we gather.
• Information You Give Us:
* When you place an order, we will need to know your company name, title, name, postal address, telephone number, e-mail address. This enables us to process your orders.
* When you subscribe to our Special Offers & Newsletter Mailing List, we will need to know your e-mail address and your name is optional. This enables us to keep you informed of any special offers or news. Note – you can unsubscribe at any time.
* When you place an order, we will need to know your company name, title, name, postal address, telephone number, e-mail address. This enables us to process your orders.
* When you request a price using our ‘Get a quote for this product’ form, we will need to know your name, telephone number, e-mail address. This enables us to answer your enquiry.
* When you request more information about a product using our ‘Get more information about our standard & custom made products’ form, we will need to know your name, telephone number, e-mail address. This enables us to answer your enquiry.
* When you request more information about our components using our ‘Get more information about our components’ form, we will need to know your name, telephone number, e-mail address. This enables us to answer your enquiry.
* When you get access to download our brochures or request brochures to be posted out to you by filling out our ‘Download our brochures contact form’, we will need to know your name, company name, telephone number, e-mail address, postal address. This enables us to post out brochures you requested.
• Automatic Information:
we receive and store certain types of information whenever you interact with us. For example, like many websites, we use “cookies” and we obtain certain types of information (such as how you use and navigate our website) when your Web browser accesses Shopkit Group Ltd, but all the automatic information is completely anonymous and we never harvest or collect email addresses from our website visitors.
What About Cookies?
If you are reading this you found our website somehow. We hope to get you to visit our web site by creating quality products and services that are of interest to you.
Our products and services are really for other businesses and we do what any business owner tries to do, we like to figure out what works and what doesn’t and keep improving what we do.
So cookies help us monitor the volume of visitors to our websites, how you may have found us, where you came from and which pages you view when visiting our site. At this stage we do not know who you are, just that some people arrive from here and go there. We do not harvest or collect email addresses from website visitors. If you don’t contact us and give us your email, we don’t have your details.
Cookies enable us to use things like google analytics which help us improve on what we include on our websites.
Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that we transfer to your computer’s hard drive through your Web browser to enable our systems to recognise your browser. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to you and they do not contain personally identifying information. The Help menu on the menu bar of most browsers will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie and how to disable cookies altogether.
We use a number of different cookies on our site.  The list below describes the cookies we use on this site and what we use them for. Currently we operate an ‘implied consent’ policy which means that we assume you are happy with this usage.
If you are not happy, then you should either: browse the site using your browser’s anonymous usage setting (called “Incognito” in Chrome, “InPrivate” for Internet Explorer, “Private Browsing” in Firefox and Safari etc.), delete the cookies having visited the site, or you should refrain from using this site.
• First Party Cookies: These are cookies that are set by this website directly.
• Google Analytics: We use Google Analytics to collect information about visitor behaviour on our website. Google Analytics stores information about what pages you visit, how long you are on the site, how you got here and what you click on. This Analytics data is collected via a JavaScript tag in the pages of our site and is not tied to personally identifiable information.We therefore do not collect or store your personal information (e.g. your name or address) so this information cannot be used to identify who you are.
You can find out more about Google’s position on privacy as regards its analytics service at https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245
• When signing in to our online shop and using the Shopping Cart: We use a session cookie to remember your log-in for you and what you’ve put in the shopping basket.  A session cookie is a piece of text that is written to the browser’s memory when specific Web pages are opened (at the beginning of a session). This session cookie provides the authorisation details needed for you to use all the functions on the Web site. After signing out or closing your browser (to end a session), the session cookie is deleted.
These we deem strictly necessary to the working of the website. If these are disabled then various functionality on the site will be broken.  More information on session cookies and what they are used for at www.allaboutcookies.org/cookies/session-cookies-used-for.html
Controlling Information About You?
When you fill in a form or provide your details on our website, you will see a tick box allowing you to: Opt-in to receiving marketing communications from us by email.  If you have agreed that we can use your information for marketing purposes, you can change your mind easily via one of these methods:
• Sign in to our website and change your opt-in settings.
• Unsubscribe when you receive an marketing email; you’ll find the link at the bottom of every email
• Send an email to E: sales@shopkit.com
• Write to us at: Data Controller Shopkit Group Ltd, Unit 3, Swanstons Road, Great Yarmouth, Norfolk, NR30 3NQ.
Does Shopkit Group Ltd Share the Information They Receive?
• Information about our customers is an important part of our business and we are not in the business of selling it to others. Shopkit Group Ltd shares customer information only as described below and is either subject to this Privacy Notice or follows practices at least as protective as those described in this Privacy Notice.
• Third Party Service Providers: We employ other companies and individuals to perform functions on our behalf. Examples include fulfilling orders, delivering packages, sending postal mail and e-mail, removing repetitive information from customer lists, analysing data, providing marketing assistance, providing search results and links (including paid listings and links), processing credit card payments and providing customer service. They have access to personal information needed to perform their functions, but may not use it for other purposes. Further, they must process the personal information in accordance with this Privacy Notice and as permitted by the UK’s Data Protection Act. EU’s GDPR May 2018.
• Payment: Payment: If you purchase from our Online Shop or through our Sales Department your payment details are processed completely safely and separately by Worldpay.
• Business Transfers: As we continue to develop our business, we might sell or buy stores, subsidiaries or business units. In such transactions, customer information generally is one of the transferred business assets but remains subject to the promises made in any pre-existing Privacy Notice (unless, of course, the customer consents otherwise). Also, in the unlikely event that Shopkit Group Ltd or substantially all of its assets are acquired, customer information will of course be one of the transferred assets.
•Shopkit Designs Ltd and Others: We release account and other personal information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law; enforce or apply our Conditions of Use and other agreements; or protect the rights, property or safety of Shopkit Group Ltd, our users or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for fraud protection and credit risk reduction. Obviously, however, this does not include selling, renting, sharing or otherwise disclosing personally identifiable information from customers for commercial purposes in a way that is contrary to the commitments made in this Privacy Notice.
How Secure Is Information About Me?
• We work to protect the security of your information during transmission by using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software, which encrypts information you input.
• We maintain physical, electronic and procedural safeguards in connection with the collection, storage and disclosure of personally identifiable customer information. Our security procedures mean that we may occasionally request proof of identity before we disclose personal information to you.
• How we store our paper records – Invoices/Files/ledger Books etc. are all kept confidential by Company Staff and they are not available for general access.
• How we store our computer records – All computer records are stored on password protected computers and any changes or updates to these records are controlled internally and NOT available outside of the Company.
• It is important for you to protect against unauthorised access to your password and to your computer. Be sure to sign off when you finish using a shared computer.
What About Third-Party Advertisers and Links to Other Websites?
We do not include third party advertising on our websites and only include links to our trusted distributors, but your information is never automatically shared with them.
Conditions of Use, Notices, and Revisions
If you choose to visit Shopkit Group Ltd, you consent to the collection and use of this information. Your visit and any dispute over privacy are subject to this Privacy Notice. Any changes to this Privacy Statement will be posted on this page.
If you have any concern about privacy at Shopkit Group Ltd, please e-mail us a thorough description and we will try to resolve the issue for you.
E: sales@shopkit.com
